A Guide to the Mark Kac papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA170
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Laboratory Notebooks, 1942-1964; 5; 4.84 Cubic Feet
  - 1942 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Notebook III, 1946 October (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - 1952 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - 1953 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Summer 1953 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - 1954 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - 1957 November (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - 1959 March (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - 1960s (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - 1960 January (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - 1960 July-August (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - 1961 January-June (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - 1961 March (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - 1961 September (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - 1962 January (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - 1962 October (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - 1963 January (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - 1963 February (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - 1963 April-May (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - 1963 June (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - 1963 July (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - 1963 August (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - 1964 January (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - 1964 May, Book 1 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - 1964 May, Book 2 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - 1965 January, Book 3 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - 1965 July (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - 1966 June (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - 1966 August (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - 1967 February, Book 6 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - 1967 October (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - 1968 December-1969 June (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - 1968 December (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - 1969 August (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - 1970 October (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - 1971 March (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - 1971 August (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - 197? February (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - 1973 November (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - 1974 August (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Algebra Over the Complex Number (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Analytic Number Theory (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Benel Functions (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Complex Variables (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Complex Variables-Math 531/32, 1 of 2 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Complex Variables-Math 531/32, 2 of 2 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Derivation of Boltzmann's Equation (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Ehrenfest Example (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Ehrenfest Model (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Equation of Continuity (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - 4-body Toda Problem (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Generalized Diffusion Theory (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Kinetic Theory, 1 of 2 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Kinetic Theory, 2 of 2 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Kinetic Theory and Related Topics (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Langenian Equation for a Brownian Particle (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Linear Boltzmann Equation (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Linville's Equation (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Marnoff Chains (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - "Master Equation" for the Simplified Model (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Mathematical Physics (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Mathematics 400 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Mathematics 721-22 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Matrix of Transitions Probabilities (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Method of Steepest Descent (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1 of 2 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 of 2 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous II (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Moran Models (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Non-linear Models (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Notebook, 1946 August 1 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Notebook, 1946 August 2 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Notebook, 1947 March 5 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Notebook, 1946 November 9 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - "On the Distribution of Distances of Points Chosen at Random" (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - "On the Distribution of Eigenvalues of Certain Integral Equations" (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - "On the Theory of Random Noise in Radio Receivers" (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Particle Density (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Princeton, 1951-1952 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - "Probabilistic Approach to Kinetic Theory of Gases" (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Propagation of sound in rarefied gases (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Ray's derivation of Spitzer's Theorem (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Rayleigh's treatment of convection (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Remarks on the first passage time for the Uhlenbeck-Ornstein Process (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Remarks on Markoff Chains (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Rotating bucket notes (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Second Law of Thermodynamics (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Spherical Model (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Statistical Mechanics Seminar Spring, 1948 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Statistical Thermodynamics (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Stellar Statistics (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Three-body Toda problem (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Theory of Random Process, 1948 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Translation Kernels (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Two-dimensional Markoff Process (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Uhlenbeck's Notebook on Quantum Electrodynamics (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - [unidentified] (Box 55, Folder 9)
- Audio-Visual Material, 1960s; 6; 0.5 Cubic Feet
  Recordings of several lectures and 14 glass slides, unidentified.
  Arranged in chronological order by title of lecture.
  - "Role of Mathematical Models in Science", 1969 February 12 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Open for research. Digital access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  - "How to Hear the Shape of a Drum", 1964 August; Takes 1-9 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - "How to Hear the Shape of a Drum", 1964 August; Takes 10-16 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - "How to Hear the Shape of a Drum", 1964 August; Takes 17-22 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - "Computer Music" (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - "Wiener" (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - [unidentified reel] (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - 14 unidentified glass slides, 1964 (Box 56)
- Student Thesis, 1940-1982; 7; 1.32 Cubic Feet
  Includes students' theses who had been advised by Kac.
  Arranged in alphabetical order by student's last name.
  - Eustaquio S. Baclig, Jr., 1953 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Harlan G.H. Bartram, 1950 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Donald Elro Bedo, 1957 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Jack Logan Bellamy, 1950 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Martin Roy Bates, 1949 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Tseng Tung Cheng, 1949 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Robert Cohen, 1956 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Joanne Elliott, 1949 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Ernest Slavko Elyash, 1950 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Charles Hatfield Jr., 1944 (Box 58)
  - James Henry Hayes (Box 58)
  - Phillip S. Jastram (Box 58)
  - Mario Leon Juncosa, 1945 (Box 58)
  - Talbot Michael Katz, 1982 (Box 58)
  - Harry Kesten, 1958 (Box 58)
  - Abraham Morton Mark, 1945 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Abraham Morton Mark, 1947 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Henry S. McGaughan, 1949 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - David Frederick Neu, 1960 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - David S. Newman, 1963 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Alfred Milton Peiser, 1944 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Murray Rosenblatt, 1949 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Irma Schocken, 1946 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Jerome C. Smith, 1945 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Murray R. Spiegel, 1949 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Alan Gustave Konheim, 1960 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Paul Joseph Lochak, 1951 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - William Judson Leveque, 1947 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Charles C. Torrance, 1927 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Michael Waldner, 1948 (Box 60, Folder 6)
- Personal File, 1939-1984; 8; 0.25 Cubic Feet
  Includes biographical material and photographs.
  Arranged in chronological order.
  - Biographical material (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Photographs (Box 61, Folder 2)
- Reprints, Papers, Lectures, and Correspondence Files, Accession 2006:064, 1934-1986; 9; 11.83 Cubic Feet 9 record storage boxes.
  - "Statistical Mechanics of Some One-Dimensional Systems," Reprint, 1962 (Box 1)
  - "A History-Dependent Random Sequence Defined by Ulam," Reprint, 1970 (Box 1)
  - "Some More on "What is Random?," Manuscript (Box 1)
  - "Will Computers Replace Humans?," Manuscript, 1974 (Box 1)
  - "Memoir of a Physicist," Science, Reprint, Review, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Mathematical Manuscript (Box 1)
  - "The Search for the Meaning of Independence," Manuscript, Chapter III (Box 1)
  - Manuscript (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscriptions (Box 1)
  - "The Themes and Trends of Mathematics," Manuscript (Box 1)
  - "Cornell II," Manuscript, Chapter VI (Box 1)
  - "Liquefaction," Manuscript (Box 1)
  - "Mathematics: Trends and Tensions," Reprint (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Reprints by Richard Durrett and David Griffeath (Box 1)
  - "On the Quantum Langevin Equation," by Mark Kac and Rafael Benguria, Manuscript (Box 1)
  - "Quantum Langevin Equation," Physical Review Letters, by Rafael Benguria and Mark Kac, Reprint, 1981 (Box 1)
  - "A Complete Solution on the Periodic Toda Problem," Proc. National Academy of Science, by Mark Kac and Pierre van Moerbeke, Reprint, 1975 (Box 1)
  - "What is Random?: Marginalia," American Scientist, Pre-print, 1983 (Box 1)
  - "Wiener and Integration in Function Spaces," Reprint (Box 1)
  - "On Some Isospectral Second Order Differntial Operators," Proc. National Academy of Science, by Mark Kac and PIerre van Moerbeke, Reprint, 1974 (Box 1)
  - "Critical Behavior oof Several Lattice Models with Long Range Interaction," Journal of Mathematical Physics, by Mark Kac and Colin Thompson, Reprint, 1969 (Box 1)
  - "Relativistic Extension of the Analogy Between Quantum Mechanics and Brownian Motion," Physical Review Letters, by G. Gaveau, T. Jackson, Mark Kac, and L. S. Schulman, Reprint, 1984 (Box 1)
  - "Study of Several Lattice Systems with Long-Range Forces," Journal of Mathematical Physics, by Mark Kac and E. Helfand, Reprint, 1984 (Box 1)
  - "Wie ich Mathematiker wurde," Reprint (Box 1)
  - "Marginalia: Dehydrated Elephants Revisited," American Scientist, Reprint, 1982 (Box 1)
  - "Marginalia: More on Randomness," American Scientist, Reprint, 1984 (Box 1)
  - "Marginalia: What is Random?," American Scientist, Reprint, 1983 (Box 1)
  - "Marginalia: Florence Nightingale Among the Statisticians," American Scientist, Reprint, 1984 (Box 1)
  - "A Mathematician Looks at Medicine," The American Journal of Medicine, Reprint, 1979 (Box 1)
  - "Theorie Mathematique des Effets du Jeu de Billard," by Par G. Coriolis, 1835 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1968-1983 (Box 1)
  - The Three Body Toda System and a Parametrization of Plane Cubic Curves," Aspects of Mathematics and its Appplications, Reprint, 1986 (Box 1)
  - MacArthur Foundation, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Rehovot, Published by The Weizmann Institute of Science and Yad Chaim Weizmann, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - "Stochastic Processes," Manuscript (Box 1)
  - "Chance and Regularity," Manuscript, 1962 (Box 1)
  - "Propagation of Chaos and Burgers Equation," E. Gutkin and Mark Kac, Manuscript, American Scientist, "Marginalia", 1983 July-August (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Reprints and Articles (Box 1)
  - Bose-Einstein Gas (Box 1)
  - Case Institute of Technology, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Coding Theorems of Information Theory by J. Wolfowitz, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Conversations wiht Joel, I (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscripts and Reprints (Box 1)
  - Kac, Marc, Oral History (Incomplete), 1980 (Box 1)
  - "Special Problems of Statistical Mechanics, Part II," Lectures by C. N. Yang, University of Washington, 1952 (Box 1)
  - "The Youngest Science" Notes of Medicine-Watcher," by Lewis Thomas (Box 1)
  - "Some Applications of Functional Integration to Classical and Bose Condensation," by F. W, Wiegel (Box 1)
  - "Quantum Completely Integrable Models Theory," by L. D. Faddeev, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Manuscript (Box 1)
  - Discrete Lax Equations and Differential-Difference Calculus," by B. A. Kuperschmidt, Manuscript (Box 1)
  - "Special Problems of Statistical Mechanics-Part I" Lectures by C. N. Yang, University of Washington, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Work by Others Acknowledging Mark Kac (Box 2)
  - Pertaining to Election to National Academy of Science (NAS) (Box 2)
  - Journalistic Coverage of Mark Kac (Box 2)
  - Random Wak and Bird Navigation (Box 2)
  - Linnik, Y. V. (Box 1)
  - Manhattanville Lecture (Box 2)
  - Chauvenet Prize (Box 2)
  - "Methods of Theoretical Physics," P. M. Morse, Feshbach, B. AMS 62, 52(56), 124, Review (Box 2)
  - Correspondence Expressing Condolences for the Death of Mark Kac, 1984-1986 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence Expressing Concern for Mark Kac's Health (Box 2)
  - Correspondence Regarding Mark Kac's Books and Lectures (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correpondence (Box 2)
  - AAAS holiday Science Lectures, Los Angeles, (Glass Slides), Slides for Lectures III and IV (Box 2)
  - Case, Ken, Notes (Box 3)
  - Minzoni, Tim (Box 3)
  - The Annals of Probability, An Official Journal of The Institute of Mathematical Statistics, Vol. 10, No. 2, 1982 May (Box 3)
  - Fylakra, maandblad rond de utrechtse fysika, Jaargang 24, NR.2 (Box 3)
  - Advances in Mathematics, Vol. 16, No.2, 1975 May (Box 3)
  - Advances in Applied Matematics, 1982 March-1985 June (Box 3)
  - "The Role of Models in Understandng Phase Transitions," Reprints (Box 3)
  - "On Rapidly Mixing Transformations and an Application to Continued Fractions," Bulletin of American Mathematical Society, Reprint, 1958 September (Box 3)
  - "The Harold Carmer Volume," of Probability and Staistics, Ed. by Ulf Grenander, Reprint (Box 3)
  - L'Enseignement Mathematique Revue Internationale, Commission, Reprint (Box 3)
  - Internationale de L'Enseignement Mathematique, 1969 (Box 3)
  - "A Class of Limit Theorems," Transactions of the American Mathematical Society, Reprint, 1957 March (Box 3)
  - "Can One Hear the Shape of a Drum?," American Mathematical Monthly, Reprint, 1966 April (Box 3)
  - "Some Analytic Aspects of Probabilistic Potential Theory," Zasosowania Matematyki Applicationes Mathematicae, Reprint, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Nordia Publications, "On Certain Toeplitz-like Matrices and Their Relation to the Problem of Lattice Vibrations," No. 286, 1968 (Box 3)
  - "Analysis of Basic Queuing Problem Arising in Computer Systems," IBM Journal of Research and Development, Reprintf, 1961 April (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1937-1939 (Box 3)
  - "Some Mathematical Problems Suggested by Questions in Physics," American Mathematical Society 87th Annual Colloquium Lectures, Reprint, 1981 (Box 3)
  - "An Introduction to Infinite Particle Systems," by Richard Durrett, Stochastic Processes and Their Applications, Reprint, 1981 (Box 3)
  - "On the Growth of Dimensional Contract Processes," by Richard Durrett, THe Annals of Probability, Reprint, 1980 (Box 3)
  - "Probabilistic Methods in Some Problems of Scattering Theory," The Rocky Mountain Journal of Mathematics, Reprint, 1974 (Box 3)
  - International Symposium on Stochastic Differential Equations, Vilnius, "Abstracts of Communications", 1978 August 28-September 2 (Box 3)
  - "The Three Body Toda System and a Parameterization of Plane Cubic Curves," Aspects of Mathematics and its Applications, Reprint, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1985 (Box 3)
  - Bibliography (Box 3)
  - Kac, Mark, Personal (Box 3)
  - American Scientist, 1983 July-August (Box 3)
  - "Wiener and Integration in Function Spaces," Bulletin of the American Mathematical Society, Reprint, 1966 January (Box 3)
  - "The Ideal Bose-Einstein Gas, Revisited," by R. M. Ziff, G. E. Uhlenbeck, and Mark Kac, Physics Reports, 1977 September (Box 3)
  - Boston University Journal, 1976 (Box 3)
  - "Aspects Probabilistes de la Theorie du Potentiel," Seminaire de Mathematiques Superieures, 1970 (Box 3)
  - "Lectures in Probability" (Box 3)
  - A Trigonometicals Series, J. London Math. Society 9, 1934 (Box 4)
  - O stochastycznej niezaleznosci funkcyi, Warsaw, 1937 (Box 4)
  - Une remarque sur les series trigonometriques, Studia Mathematica, 5, 99-102, 1935 (Box 4)
  - Sur les functions independantes (1), Studia Mathematica, VI, 46-58, 1936 (Box 4)
  - H. Steinhaus, Mark Kac, Theorie des functions, 1936 (Box 4)
  - H. Steinhaus, Mark Kac, Theorie des functions, 1936 (Box 4)
  - (H. Steinhaus) Sur les functions independantes (IV), Studia Mathematica, 7. 1-15, 1937 (Box 4)
  - On the van der Waals Theor of Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium, III, Journal Math. Physics, 5, 60-74, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Sur Les functios independantes (V), Studia Mathematica, VII, 96-100, 1937 (Box 4)
  - Une remarque sue les polynomes de M. S. Bernstein, Studia Mathematica, 7, 49-51, 1937 (Box 4)
  - Une remarque sur les equations fonctionelles, Comm. Math. Helvet, 9, 1936 (Box 4)
  - Quelques remarques sur les zeros des integrals de Fourier, J. London Math. Society, 13, 128-130, 1938 (Box 4)
  - Sur les functions 2nt-(2nt)-1/2, J. London Math. Soc., 13, 131-134, 1938 (Box 4)
  - On a Problem Concerning Probability and Its Connection with the Theory of Diffusion, Bull. A, Math. Soc., 46, 534-537, 1940 (Box 4)
  - P. Erdos, E. T.. v. Kampen, A. Wintner Ramanujan Sums and Almost Periodic Functions, Studia. Matha., IX (I), 43, 1940 (Box 4)
  - Almost Periodicity and Representation of Integers as Sums of Squares, Am. J. Math., 62, 122-126, 1940 (Box 4)
  - Partial Sums of the Exponential Series, Mex., Math Y Fis. Teoretica, 3, 1942 (Box 4)
  - On the Average Number of Real Roots of a Random Algebraic Equation, AMS Bull., 49, 314, 1943 (Box 4)
  - On the Distribution of Values of Trigonometric Sumes with Linerarly ind. Frequc., American Journal of Math., 61, 1942 (Box 4)
  - H. Hurwitz, Statistical Analysis of Certain Types of Random Functions, Ann. Math., 15, 173-181, 1944 (Box 4)
  - Random Walk in the Presence of Absorbg. Barriers, Ann. Math., 16, 62-67, 1945 (Box 4)
  - Remark on Independene of Linear and Quadraatic Forms Involving Independent Gaussian Variables, Ann. Math. Stat, 16, 1945 (Box 4)
  - On the Distribution of Values of Sums of the Type (Sigma)c(2kt), Ann. of Math., 47, 33-49, 1946 (Box 4)
  - On the Average of Certain Wiener Functional and a Related Limit Theorem in Calculus of Probty, Trans. Am. Math. Soc., 59, 401-414, 1946 (Box 4)
  - AJF Siegert, Theory of Noise in Radio Receivers, J. Appl. Phys., 18, 383-397, 1947 (Box 4)
  - P., Erdos, On the Number of Positive Sums of Indep, Random Variables, Bull. Am. Math. Soc., 53, 1011-1020, 1947 (Box 4)
  - On the Notion of Recurrence in Discrete Stochastic Processes, Bull. Am. Math. Soc., 53, 1002-1010, 1947 (Box 4)
  - Random Walk and the Theory of Brownian Motion, AM. Math. Monthly, 54, 369-391, 1947 (Box 4)
  - (Siegert) An Explicit Representation of a Stationary Gaussian Process, Annuls. Math. Stats., 18, 438-442, 1947 (Box 4)
  - R. Salem, A. Zygmund, A Gap Theorem Transacts, Am. Math. Soc., 63, 235-243, 1948 (Box 4)
  - On the Characteristic Functions of Distributions of Estimates..., Am. Math. Stats., 19, 257-261, 1948 (Box 4)
  - On Distributions of Certain Wiener Functionals, Transacts., Am. Math. Soc., 65, 1-13, 1949 (Box 4)
  - On Deviations Between Theoretical and Empritical Disbtrutions, Proc. NAS, 35, 252-257, 1949 (Box 4)
  - On the Average Number of Real Roots of a Random Algebraic Equation (II), Proc. London Mat. Soc., 50, 390-408, 1949 (Box 4)
  - Probability Methods in Some Problems of Analysis and Number Theory, Bull. Am. Math. Soc., 55, 641-665, 1949 (Box 4)
  - Distribution Problem in the Theory of Random Noise, Proc. Symposia Appl. Maths., 2, 87-88, 1950 (Box 4)
  - H. Pollard, Partial Sums of Independent Random Variables, Can. J. Math., 2, 375-384, 1950 (Box 4)
  - K. L. Chung, Remarks on Fluctuations, Memoirs AMS, No. 6, 1950 (Box 4)
  - On Some Connections Between Probability Theory and Differential and Integral Equations, PProc. 2nd Bferkeley Symp., 1951 (Box 4)
  - On a Theorem of Zygmund, Proc. Cambridge Philos. Soc., 47, 475-476, 1951 (Box 4)
  - M. D. Donsker, Sampling Model...NBS, Res. Paper RP 2102, 44, 1950 (Box 4)
  - T. H. Berlin, Spherical Model of a Ferromagnet, Phys. Rev, 86, 821-835, 1952 (Box 4)
  - J. C. Ward, A Combinatorial Solution of the 2-dimensional Ising Model, Phys. Rev., 88, 1332-1337, 1952 (Box 4)
  - W. Murdock, G. Szego, On the Eigen-value of Certain Hermitian Forms, J. Rat. Mech and Analysis, 2, 767-800, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Signal and Noise Problems, Amer. Math. Monthly, 61, 23-26, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Foundations of Kinetic THeory, Proceedings of 3rd Berkeley Symposium on Mathl. Stats. and Prob., UCLA, 3, 171-197, 1955 (Box 4)
  - A Remark on the Preceding Paper by Renyi, Ac. Serbe des Sciences Extraits Inst. Math, Beograd, 8, 1955 (Box 4)
  - J. Kiefer, J. Woolfowitz, On Tests of Normality and Other Tests of Goodness, Annals. Math. Stat., 26, 189-211, 1956 (Box 4)
  - Some Remarks on the Use of Probability in Classical Statisical Mechanics, Bull. Ac. Royl. Belge., Ser. 5, 42, 356, 1956 (Box 4)
  - Probability in Classical Physics, Proc. 7th Symp. Appld. Math. McGraw Hil, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Toeplitz Matrices, Transation Kernels and a Related Problem in Prob. Theory, Duke Math J., 21, 501-509, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Distribution of Eigenvalues of Certain Integral Operators, Much. Math. J., 3, 141-148, 1955-1956 (Box 4)
  - D. A. Darling, On Occupation Times for Markoff Processes, Trans. AMS, 84, 444-458, 1957 (Box 4)
  - A Class of Limit Theorems, Transact. AMS, 84, 459-471, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Uniform Distribution on a Sphere, Bull. Ac. Polonaise des Sciences, Cl. III, 5, 485-486, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Some Remarks on Stable Processes, Cornell University, 303-306, 1957-1958 (Box 4)
  - Remarks on Stable Processes with Indep. Increments, Probability and Statistics, Harald Cramer vol., 130-138, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Toeplitz Forms and Their Applications Review: U. Renander, G. Szego, Science, 128, 137-138, 1958 (Box 4)
  - On Rapidly Mixing Transfoormations and an Applicaiton to Continued Fractions, Bull. AMS, 64, 283-287, 1958 (Box 4)
  - D. Slepian, Large Excursions of Gaussian Processes, Ann. Mathl. Stats., 30, 1215-1228, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Book w Hiibbs, Pol, Uhlenbeck, Boulder Lects., "Probability and Related Topics in Physical Sciences", 1957, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Some Remarks On Oscillators Driven by a Random Force, IRE Transactions CT., 476-479, 1960 December (Box 4)
  - Chance and Regularity, 1962 December (Box 4)
  - Probability Theory as Mathl. Disipline and Tool in Engineering and Science, Pro. 1st Symposium on Engineering, 31-67, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Can One Hear the Shape of a Drum? Amer. Mathl., 73, 1-23, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Asympotomatic Behaviour of a Class of Determinants, Enseignement Math., 15, 177-183, 1969 (Box 4)
  - On Some Probabilistic Aspects of Classical Analysis, Am. Math. Monthy, 77, 586-597, 1970 (Box 4)
  - The Role of Models in Understanding Phase Transitions (Battelle 971970), Critl. Phen. In Alloys, Mills, Ascher, Jaffee, McGraw-Hill, 23-39, 1971 (Box 4)
  - C. J. Thompson, Spherical Model and the Infinite Spin Dimensionality Limit, Physica Norvegica, 5, 163-168, 1971 (Box 4)
  - On Applying Mathematics: Reflections and Examples, Quarterly Appl. Maths. (Special Issue), 30, 17-29, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Possible Origin of the Quantized Vortices in He II, w. Putterman and Uhenbeck, Phys. Rev. Lts., 29, 546, 1972 (Box 4)
  - William Feller in Memoriam, Proceedings 6th Berkeley Symp., U. Cal., 1970 June-July, 1973 (Box 4)
  - A Discrete Version of the Inverse Scattering Problem, J. Math. Phys., 14, 594-603, 1973 (Box 4)
  - The Emergence of Statistical Thought in Exact Sciences, The Heritage of Copernicus, MIT Press, 443-444, 1974 (Box 4)
  - On Some Periodic Toda Lattices, With P. van Moerbeke, Proc. NAS, 72, 1627-1629, 1975 (Box 4)
  - The Ideal Bose-Einstein Gas, Polskiej Akademi NAUK, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Phenomenes Stochastiques and Theorie des Fluctuations, Lausanne, 1974 (Box 4)
  - An Example of "Counting without Counting" Phillips, Res. Repts. (886) 30, 20-22 (in Honor of C. J. Bouwkamp_), 1975 (Box 4)
  - Moerbeke, V., A Complete Solution of the Periodic Toda Problem, Proc. NAS, 72, 2879-2880, 1975 (Box 4)
  - The Social Responsibility of the Ac. Community, Journal of the Franklin Institute, 300, 2, 125-127, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Some Reflections of a Mathematician on the Nature and the Role of Statistics, Suppl. Adv. Appl. Prob., 7, 5-11, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Barrett, W., On Some Modified Spherical Models, Proc. NAS, 72, 4723-4724, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Logan, J., Fluctuations and the Boltzmann Equation, I, Phys. Rev. A, 458-470, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Lebesgue, Henri, L'Enseignement Math., 21, 11-114, 1975 (Box 4)